I'm going to show you how to use the Janowak head harness.
What it's designed for is to help pulling dogs.
With a dog on a regular flat collar or a Martingale which this is, when he gets ahead of you, I got give him a pull back, I got to use a little bit more strength.
If I get walking with him and he wants to get a head of me, I got to pull him a little bit more.
He's not pulling real bad now.
We get going with something, come on, come on.
I have to encourage him a little bit more.
With the head harness, once you hook it up, I can guide him around a little bit easier.
You want to remember to never yank, never pull, never leash pop.
Always use a slow fluid movement.
Any kind of fussing or fidgeting, get your treats out, coax him with you.
Good boy.
Turn him around, lots of treats.
Get a good walk going.
I can bring him around, I can bring him next to me, and I can reward him for staying by my side.
It keeps him nice and calm as long as he is not fussing around.